<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>user-interaction on Ayush Subedi</title>
    <link>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/tags/user-interaction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in user-interaction on Ayush Subedi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ayushsubedi.github.io/tags/user-interaction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>(Work in progress) Human-Computer Interaction</title>
      <link>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/human_computer_interaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/human_computer_interaction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;human-computer-interaction&#34;&gt;Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-to-hci&#34;&gt;Introduction to HCI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The goal is to create a scenario where user spends as much time as possible to accomplish the task, while the interface kind of vanishes during that interaction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A video game, as an example gives the user an experience of being in the game, not tinkering with the controller&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We might be experts at interacting with computers, but that does not make us experts at designing interactions between other humans and computers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HCI is a subset of Human Factors Engineering (Industrial Design, HCI, Product Design)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UI Design and UX Design and Interaction Design are a subset of HCI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many principle of HCI come from Human Factors Engineering applied to computers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tha gap between HCI and Interaction Design is shrinking (as computers become ubiquitious)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HCI is about understanding the interaction between users and computers, and UX design is about dictating the interaction between users and computer. The relationship is howerver, deeply symbiotic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Human Factors Engineering is a merger of Engineering and Psychology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Psychology and HCI are also deeply symbiotic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HCI is about research (needfinding, prototyping, evaluation) and design (distributed cognnition, mental models, universal design)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HCI at its core: Research informs Design and Design informs Research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;exploring-hci&#34;&gt;Exploring HCI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technologies : Virtual Reality, Augmented Reality, UbiComp and Wearables, Robotics, Mobile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ideas: Context-Sensitive Computing, Gesture-Based Interaction, Pen-and Touch-Based Interaction, Information Visualization, CSCW (Computer Supported Cooperative Work) Interaction (Distributed Team, Distributed Work, Temporal and Geographical dimension): Example: Slack, Online course, etc., Social Computing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Domain: Special Needs (example: communicating data using sound for visually impaired people), Education (you might not always want to make something super easy), Healthcare (fitbit, virtual reality), Security (for security to be useful, it has to be usable). Captcha has become easy now with a checkbox, Games (topics of HCI are super salient here)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-to-principles&#34;&gt;Introduction to Principles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;user uses interfaces to accomplish a task&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;need to userstand the user goals and the task&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;focusing on task and not the interface, allows us to come up with something amazing (nest instead of iteration on thermostat)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to identify a task?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;watch real users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;talk to them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;start small (look at individual interaction)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;abstract up (why are they &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; performing?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you are not your user&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goals of HCI:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;useful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;usable (the big concern)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If we were focusing on building better maps, we would not add navigation (think about what the user wants)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ex situ&lt;/strong&gt; - in a controlled or otherwise inauthentic environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In situ&lt;/strong&gt; - within the authentic context&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three roles a human can play:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;processor&#34;&gt;Processor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nothing more than Sensory processor, take input and spit output out,  like another computer in the system, interface must fit within known human limits: (what humans can sense, what they can store in memory, and what they can physically do in the world)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;usability: interface is physically usable (users can see colors, touch the buttons etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;evaluated by quantitative methods. - - &amp;ldquo;Behaviorism&amp;rdquo; from psychology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how quickly can the user complete the task?, how quickly can they react to incoming stimulus?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The processor model is concerned with objective, measurable outcomes, so noting the efficiency with which you can accomplish different tasks is relevant here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;control study&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;interfaces and get the timing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pros
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use existing data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Objective comparison (text v/s voice).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reason is not visible
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;why text is not better than voice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Novice confusing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suitable for only evaluation and optimization, not redesign.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;predictor&#34;&gt;Predictor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask interviews and focus groups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get full details on textual description&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why use different interfaces at different time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;why choice, why particular option&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cognitivism&amp;rdquo; from psychology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;here we care about the users knowledge, experience, expectation and thought process, we want users to predict what will happen, what are they thinking, interface must fit with knowledge, evaluated by qualitative studies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The predictor model is concerned with what you predict will be the outcome of your action, and whether you can interpret whether the outcome matched your prediction, so focus on how the user perceives and interprets what they should do and whether it was successful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The predictor model is not about interfaces predicting users intentions. The predictor model is about paying attention to what the user predicts the outcome of their action will be, and how they will interpret what they see after their action is complete.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pros
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More complete picture of interaction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Caters for experts and novices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cons
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analysis is costly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bias in analysis. Focus on specific set of data points.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ignore broader context.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ex Only person and interface. Example maps in driving vs map in labs. *5 sec disappearence of search bar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;participant&#34;&gt;Participant&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider broader activity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;not just inside their head but outside world, interface must fit with context, evaluted by in-situ studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Functionalism/Systems Psychology&amp;rdquo; from psychology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pros&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluates interaction in context&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Capture authentic user attentions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expensive analysis to perform and analyze both&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Requires real functional interfaces, no prototypes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hard to use when starting fresh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lots of uncontrollable variables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Each design informs one another&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;feedback-cycles&#34;&gt;Feedback Cycles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;way in which people interact with the world and get feedback on the results of those interactions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ubiquity of feedback cycles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feedback cycles are hallmark of AI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Gulf of Execution is a term used in the field of human-computer interaction to describe the gap between a user&amp;rsquo;s goals or intentions and the actions they must take in order to achieve those goals using a computer system. The gulf of execution refers to the difficulty or complexity a user may experience in understanding and using the system to accomplish their task. The term is often used in contrast to the Gulf of Evaluation, which refers to the difficulty a user may have in understanding the results or feedback provided by a system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gulf-of-execution&#34;&gt;Gulf of execution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;distance between user&amp;rsquo;s goals and the execution of the actions required to realize those goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how do the users know what they can do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how do the users figure out how to make those goals a reality?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how do they figure out what actions to take to make the state of the system match their goal state?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how hard is it to do in the interface what is necessary to accomplish the goals?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what is the difference between what the user thinks they have to do vs what they actually have to do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify Intentions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify Intentions &lt;strong&gt;in the context of the system&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify Actions necessary to make the goal a reality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Execute in Interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gulf-of-evaluation&#34;&gt;Gulf of evaluation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the distance between the effects of those actions and the user&amp;rsquo;s understanding of the results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the output of the action that the user took&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interface Output (visual or sound)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interpretation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluation (whether or not the goal was accomplished/realized within the system)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tips-for-gulf-of-evaluation&#34;&gt;Tips for Gulf of evaluation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give feedback constantly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give feedback immediately&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Match the feedback to the action (Subtle action, subtle feedback; signification action, significant feedback )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vary your feedback (auditory, haptic etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leverage direct manipulation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;normans-feedback-cycle-stage&#34;&gt;Norman&amp;rsquo;s Feedback Cycle Stage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The goal: what do I want to accomplish and why?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plan: how can I do it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specify: what options do I have?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perform: what can I do now?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perceive: what just happened?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interpret: what does it mean?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compare: is this okay? Have I accomplished my goal?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>