<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hci on Ayush Subedi</title>
    <link>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/categories/hci/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hci on Ayush Subedi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ayushsubedi.github.io/categories/hci/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Human-Computer Interaction</title>
      <link>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/human_computer_interaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/human_computer_interaction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;human-computer-interaction&#34;&gt;Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;11-introduction-to-hci&#34;&gt;1.1 Introduction to HCI&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The goal is to create a scenario where user spends as much time as possible to accomplish the task, while the interface kind of vanishes during that interaction.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A video game, as an example gives the user an experience of being in the game, not tinkering with the controller.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We might be experts at interacting with computers, but that does not make us experts at designing interactions between other humans and computers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HCI is a subset of Human Factors Engineering (Industrial Design, HCI, Product Design).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UI Design and UX Design and Interaction Design are a subset of HCI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many principle of HCI come from Human Factors Engineering applied to computers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tha gap between HCI and Interaction Design is shrinking (as computers become ubiquitious).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HCI is about understanding the interaction between users and computers, and UX design is about dictating the interaction between users and computer. The relationship is howerver, deeply symbiotic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Human Factors Engineering is a merger of Engineering and Psychology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Psychology and HCI are also deeply symbiotic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HCI is about research (needfinding, prototyping, evaluation) and design (distributed cognition, mental models, universal design).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HCI at its core: Research informs Design and Design informs Research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;13-exploring-hci&#34;&gt;1.3 Exploring HCI&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three main application areas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technologies&lt;/strong&gt;: Virtual Reality, Augmented Reality, UbiComp and Wearables, Robotics, Mobile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ideas&lt;/strong&gt;: Context-Sensitive Computing (equipping user interfaces with historical, geographical, or other forms of contextual knowledge), Gesture-Based Interaction (interacting with interfaces using hand or body gestures), Pen-and Touch-Based Interaction, Information Visualization (representing abstract data visually to help humans understand it), CSCW (Computer Supported Cooperative Work) Interaction (Distributed Team, Distributed Work, Temporal and Geographical dimension): Example: Slack, Online course, etc., Social Computing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Domain&lt;/strong&gt;: Special Needs (example: communicating data using sound for visually impaired people), Education (you might not always want to make something super easy), Healthcare (fitbit, virtual
reality), Security (for security to be useful, it has to be usable). Captcha has become easy now with a checkbox, Games (topics of HCI are super salient here)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;21-introduction-to-principles&#34;&gt;2.1 Introduction to Principles&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User uses interfaces to accomplish a task&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Need to userstand the user goals and the task&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focusing on task and not the interface, allows us to come up with something amazing (nest instead of iteration on thermostat)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to identify a task?
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watch real users&lt;/strong&gt; - get people and ask them to work with you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Talk to them&lt;/strong&gt; - talkthrough the user&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start small&lt;/strong&gt; - find small task which user performs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract up&lt;/strong&gt; - keep asking why till you reach beyond scope of design (small + small + big - series of why)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You are not your user&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goals of HCI:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Useful&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Usable&lt;/strong&gt; (the big concern)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If we were focusing on building better maps, we would not add navigation (think about what the user wants)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ex situ&lt;/strong&gt; - in a controlled or otherwise inauthentic environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In situ&lt;/strong&gt; - within the authentic context&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;viewrole-of-a-human-within-a-system&#34;&gt;View/Role of a human within a system&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;processor&#34;&gt;Processor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nothing more than Sensory processor, take input and spit output out, like another computer in the system, interface must fit within known human limits: (what humans can sense, what they can store in memory, and what they can physically do in the world)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;usability: interface is physically usable (users can see colors, touch the buttons etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;evaluated by quantitative methods/experiments. - - &amp;ldquo;Behaviorism&amp;rdquo; from psychology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how quickly can the user complete the task?, how quickly can they react to incoming stimulus?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not the one generally taken when talking about good design.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The processor model is concerned with objective, measurable outcomes, so noting the efficiency with which you can accomplish different tasks is relevant here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Control study&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;interfaces and get the timing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pros
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use existing data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Objective comparison (text v/s voice).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cons
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reason is not visible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;why text is not better than voice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cannot diffrentiate by expertise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suitable for only evaluation and optimization, not redesign.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;predictor&#34;&gt;Predictor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask interviews and focus groups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get full details on textual description&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why use different interfaces at different time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;why choice, why particular option&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cognitivism&amp;rdquo; from psychology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;here we care about the users knowledge, experience, expectation and thought process, we want users to predict what will happen, what are they thinking, interface must fit with knowledge, evaluated by qualitative studies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The predictor model is concerned with what you predict will be the outcome of your action, and whether you can interpret whether the outcome matched your prediction, so focus on how the user perceives and interprets what they should do and whether it was successful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The predictor model is not about interfaces predicting users intentions. The predictor model is about paying attention to what the user predicts the outcome of their action will be, and how they will interpret what they see after their action is complete.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pros
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More complete picture of interaction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Caters for experts and novices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cons
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analysis is costly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bias in analysis. Focus on specific set of data points.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ignore broader context. Example: Only person and interface. Example maps in driving vs map in labs. *5 sec disappearence of search bar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;participant&#34;&gt;Participant&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consider broader activity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not just inside their head but outside world, interface must fit with context, evaluted by in-situ studies (evaluated in the real world).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Functionalism/Systems Psychology&amp;rdquo; from psychology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pros
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluates interaction in context&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Capture authentic user attentions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cons
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expensive to perform and analyze both&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Requires real functional interfaces, no prototypes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hard to use when starting fresh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lots of uncontrollable variables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Each design informs one another&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ayushsubedi.github.io/img/difference_models.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;user-experience-sans-design&#34;&gt;User experience, Sans Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is always user experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UX design focuses on dictating users experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It comes due to humans and tasks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scope of user experience
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Individual&lt;/strong&gt; - Feels of design like vs deslike&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group&lt;/strong&gt; - FB keeps people in touch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Societal&lt;/strong&gt; - Twitter and Arab Spring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;22-feedback-cycles&#34;&gt;2.2 Feedback Cycles&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Way in which people interact with the world and get feedback on the results of those interactions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feedback cycles are hallmark of AI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All of HCI can be interpreted as an application of feedback cycles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Gulf of Execution is a term used in the field of human-computer interaction to describe the gap between a user&amp;rsquo;s goals or
intentions and the actions they must take in order to achieve those goals using a computer system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Gulf of Execution refers to the difficulty or complexity a user may experience in understanding and using the system to accomplish their task.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gulf-of-execution&#34;&gt;Gulf of Execution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;distance between user&amp;rsquo;s goals and the execution of the actions required to realize those goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how do the users know what they can do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how do the users figure out how to make those goals a reality?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how do they figure out what actions to take to make the state of the system match their goal state?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how hard is it to do in the interface what is necessary to accomplish the goals?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what is the difference between what the user thinks they have to do vs what they actually have to do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phases:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identify Intentions&lt;/strong&gt; (what their goal is) &lt;strong&gt;in the context of the system&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identify Actions&lt;/strong&gt; necessary to make the goal a reality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Execute in Interface&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tips-for-gulf-of-execution&#34;&gt;Tips for Gulf of Execution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make functions discoverable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let the user mess around&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be consistent with other tools - Ctrl+C for Copy, Ctrl+P for Paste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know your user - command line vs UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feed-forward - Feedforward (give what will happen if you keep doing same thing, refresh icon on facebook timeline when users drag down)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gulf-of-evaluation&#34;&gt;Gulf of evaluation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The distance between the effects of those actions and the user&amp;rsquo;s understanding of the results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The output of the action that the user took&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phases:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interface output&lt;/strong&gt; - What did it do upon action (audio/video).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interpretation&lt;/strong&gt; - Can user interpret meaning of output?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evaluation&lt;/strong&gt; - Evaluate the interpretation to check if goals was realized or not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tips-for-gulf-of-evaluation&#34;&gt;Tips for Gulf of evaluation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give feedback constantly: Give feedback at every step of the process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give feedback immediately: Let users know they have been heard (greying out icons when you click)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Match the feedback to the action (Subtle action, subtle feedback; signification action, significant feedback )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vary your feedback (auditory, haptic etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leverage direct manipulation (dragging in UI, pulling things around etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;normans-feedback-cycle-stage&#34;&gt;Norman&amp;rsquo;s Feedback Cycle Stage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The goal&lt;/strong&gt;: what do I want to accomplish and why?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plan&lt;/strong&gt;: how can I do it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Specify&lt;/strong&gt;: what options do I have?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perform&lt;/strong&gt;: what can I do now?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perceive&lt;/strong&gt;: what just happened?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interpret&lt;/strong&gt;: what does it mean?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compare&lt;/strong&gt;: Is this okay? Have I accomplished my goal?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/manikandan-ravikiran/HCI_Notes/raw/master/Test%201/Notes/img2.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/manikandan-ravikiran/HCI_Notes/raw/master/Test%201/Notes/img3.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/manikandan-ravikiran/HCI_Notes/raw/master/Test%201/Notes/img4.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;31-introduction-to-methods&#34;&gt;3.1 Introduction to Methods&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;research-methods&#34;&gt;Research Methods&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design better than existing design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In order to design interactions that are better than existing designs, it is important to take into consideration the user needs at each stage of the design process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New way to old task&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Novelty should have the purpose, and understand the users task&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;user-centered-design&#34;&gt;User Centered Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prioritizing user needs while recognizing we do not know their needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design is often done to meet some functional specification, instead of meeting the user&amp;rsquo;s need&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You are not your user&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;principles-of-user-centered-design&#34;&gt;Principles of User-Centered Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are six principles of user-centered design:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The design is based upon an explicit understanding of users, tasks, and environments - &lt;strong&gt;Do needfinding&lt;/strong&gt; Leverage this knowledge throughout the design process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users are involved throughout design and development - &lt;strong&gt;Interviews, Surveys, working on design team etc&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The design is driven and refined by user-centered evaluation. &lt;strong&gt;Real users evaluate the prototype&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The process is iterative - &lt;strong&gt;No single shot results&lt;/strong&gt;. Even after being realesed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The design addresses the whole user experience - &lt;strong&gt;Entire experience is to be considered&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The design team includes multidisciplinary skills and perspectives - &lt;strong&gt;CS Scientists, Pyschologists, Designer, Domain experts and more&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stakeholders&#34;&gt;Stakeholders&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are many types of stakeholders who user or are impacted by our interface:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Primary&lt;/strong&gt; - Our user who uses the interface directly. Grade book tool - Teachers send progress reports to parents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secondary&lt;/strong&gt; - are people who don&amp;rsquo;t use our system directly but who might interact with the output of it in some way. - Grade book tool Parents receive the output.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tertiary&lt;/strong&gt; - are people who never interact with the tool or output but who are nonetheless impacted by the existence of the tool. Grade book tool - Students&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-design-life-cycle&#34;&gt;The Design Life Cycle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User-centered design is about integrating the user into every phase of the design life cycle. We need to know two things:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What the design life cycle is?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to integrate the user into each phase?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The design life cycle in four phase:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Needfinding&lt;/strong&gt;: gather comprehensive understanding of task the user is are trying to perform: who the user is, what the context of the task is, why they are doing the task, and any other information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design alternatives&lt;/strong&gt; (early ideas on different ways to perform a task)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prototyping&lt;/strong&gt; (low fidelity to improved, so that we can put it in front of our users)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evaluation&lt;/strong&gt; (put them in front of our users)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The cycle does not end at product launch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ayushsubedi.github.io/img/design_lifecycle.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;quantitative-data&#34;&gt;Quantitative data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Descriptions, Measurements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Observations described or summarized numerically&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports formal tests, comparisons, and conclusions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is strong for a small class of things&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Captures narrow view of what we might be intereseted in examining&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;qualitative-data&#34;&gt;Qualitative data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preferences, Performances&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Observations described or summarized non-numerically&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports any kind of response or observation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Covers a broader picture of what we&amp;rsquo;re examining&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More flexible, but it is more prone to biases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Description, observations, natural language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Convert qualitative to quantitative data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How and Why&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mixed method&lt;/strong&gt;: A mixture of qualitative and quantitative data from same participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;types-of-nominal-data&#34;&gt;Types Of Nominal Data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are four main types of quantitative data:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nominal&lt;/strong&gt; - Categorical - Number of instances of different categories
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Single nominal - One category&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple nominal -  More than one category&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Binary (yes/no) and Non binary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ordinal&lt;/strong&gt; - Similar to nominal, but there is explicit ordering. Scale of 1-5. Gap is unclear.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It can be multinominal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Binary (Fail/Pass) and Non binary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interval&lt;/strong&gt; - We do know exact difference between value. Commuting between 4-6am. 64 degree celcius is not twice as warm as 32. Can be Discrete or Continious.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ratio&lt;/strong&gt; - Ratio data. Absolute value and ratio could be established. Can be Discrete or Continious.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dpbnri2zg3lc2.cloudfront.net/en/wp-content/uploads/old-blog-uploads/four-levels-of-measurement-data.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://thebiologynotes.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Nominal-Ordinal-Interval-and-Ratio-Data.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;types-of-qualitative-data&#34;&gt;Types Of Qualitative Data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depends on how its gathered&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are many types of qualitative data, below are some examples:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transcripts - Interview/Focus group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Field notes - Participant Observation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Artifacts - Reviews for Existing interfaces&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Others - Many more/ Not mentioned&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Span is a lot larger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expensive to analyze, interpretaition bias&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Qualitative data -to- Quantitative using &lt;strong&gt;coding&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We dont loose, only transformation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documented methodology is obtained (for review purposes/reproducibility)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always mix qualitative and quantittive data in HCI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Typically these transformed data are nominal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;32-ethics-and-human-research&#34;&gt;3.2 Ethics and Human Research&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;origin-of-institutional-review-board&#34;&gt;Origin Of Institutional Review Board&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Due to unethical experiments such as the &lt;em&gt;Milgram Experiment&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Tuskegee Syphilis Experiment&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Stanford Prison Experiment&lt;/em&gt; the &lt;em&gt;National Research Act&lt;/em&gt; was enacted (1974). This led to the creation of institutional review boards to oversee research at universities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In general, the benefits to society must outweigh the risks to the subjects in the case of these experiments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Belmont Report&lt;/strong&gt; - summarizes basic ethical principles that research must follow in order to receive government support.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;demanded rigoruous consent procedures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;positive outweighed negatives and rights are always preserved&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;benefits of study should outweight risk to participants&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fair selection of subjects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;value-of-research-ethics&#34;&gt;Value of Research Ethics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Benefits are worth the risk and are significant in nature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IRB is sensitive about coercisionl when participants feel coerced, it impacts our results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inherent bias on participants, effect on results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not just ethical, but doing good research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IRB also monitors the research is sound and &lt;strong&gt;useful&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;irb-protocol&#34;&gt;IRB Protocol&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Protocol is a description regarding a project&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add research personel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Protocol title&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select role&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Certification is needed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Primary Investigator (PI) will be always first, and must be a faculty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to create a protocol in IRBWISE
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Protocol description covers study at high level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research design and methodology (what users will experience and in what order)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experimental designs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Duration of participation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data collection methods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Benefits outweigh the risk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Risks are to be added.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Statistical Analysis (Qualitative research might not have this)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start and End dates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;human-subject-interaction-details&#34;&gt;Human Subject Interaction details&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will directly involve direct interaction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;describe subjects and data we plan to collect (are we being fair to all genders)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vulnerable population - special accomodation is to be needed (they might not have the ability to give full consent)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scientific justification is needed for no of participants&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Effect size is needed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inclusion and Exclusion status&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subjects age ranges&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recruitment plan - (how are we going to find our subjects)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compensation provision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;irb-consent-procedure&#34;&gt;IRB Consent Procedure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What kind of consent is received? Written or Waiver
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some narrow circumstances - Now direct effect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Waiver of documentation of consent
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Written consent is only identity of participant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implied consent and can withdraw anytime&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Justification is needed for consent waiver&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At risk population needs more information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Concealment, deception - Temporary prototype is needed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upload concent form&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-management-question&#34;&gt;Data Management Question&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clinical research and Biological research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to we keep data safe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DoD, Radiation and Nano tech - Involvement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;interview script, recruitment script, survey etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No conflict of Interest and submit to PI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;research-ethics-and-industry&#34;&gt;Research ethics and Industry&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rapid A/B Experiments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wont pass IRB and Facebook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facebook manipulate users
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;data use policy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not informed consent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;33-needfinding-and-requirements-gathering&#34;&gt;3.3 Needfinding and Requirements Gathering&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction-to-needfinding&#34;&gt;Introduction to Needfinding&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;avoid preconceived notions (if all you have is a hammer, everything looks like a nail)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Defining general questions about the user&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generating answers about the user&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Formalizing models of the users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-inventory&#34;&gt;Data Inventory&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some understanding of the data we want to gather. These are the questions we want to answer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who are the users? Age, gender, level of expertise etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where are the users? What is their environment?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the context of the task? What is competing for user attention?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are their goals? What are they trying to accomplish?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do they need? What are the physical objects/information/collaborators they need?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are their tasks? What are they doing physically, cognitively, socially?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are their subtasks? How do they accomplish those subtasks?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-problem-space&#34;&gt;The Problem Space&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where is the task occuring? What else is going on, what are the user&amp;rsquo;s explicit and implicit needs?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;broader view of the problem space&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;start with general types and observations and move through progressively more targeted types of need finding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;user-types&#34;&gt;User Types&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;full range of users for which we are designing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;task is usually the same for both, but the audience, their motivation and their needs are different&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;identify different types of user and perform needfinding exercise on all of them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;avoiding-bias-in-needfinding&#34;&gt;Avoiding Bias in Needfinding&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Confirmation bias: we see what we want to see&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Observer bias&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social desirability bias&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Volantary response bias&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recall bias&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;naturalistic-observation&#34;&gt;Naturalistic Observation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;observing people in their natural context&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cannot interact with users directly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not sure what those users are thinking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tips on Naturalistic Observation
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start specific, and then abstract (do not summarize too soon)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spread out your sessions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find a partner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look for questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;participant-observation&#34;&gt;Participant Observation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;although you are not your user, you can act as a participant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hacks-and-workarounds&#34;&gt;Hacks and Workarounds&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how do users use hacks/workarounds to accomplish a task?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;but ask them why they use the hacks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;errors&#34;&gt;Errors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;errors users make when they use an ai&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mental models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;apprenticeship-and-ethnography&#34;&gt;Apprenticeship and Ethnography&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Researching a community by becoming a participant in it (become an expert in it: pretty much)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;interviews-and-focus-groups&#34;&gt;Interviews and Focus Groups&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;just talk to them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;focus group can lead to convergent thinking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;interviews&#34;&gt;Interviews&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tips for effective interviews:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6 W&amp;rsquo;s (who, what, where, when, why and how), open ended semi structured questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;be aware of bias&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;listen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;organize the interview (introduction, lighter qn for trust gathering, summary at end for the user to understand the purpose)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;practice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;think-aloud&#34;&gt;Think-Aloud&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;asking user to think out loud while in the context of the task&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;useful because we get info that user might forget later, but thinking out loud might cause them to act differently&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post-Event Protocol (is better option)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;surveys&#34;&gt;Surveys&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;larger number of questions/surveyers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not as through, but powerful to get large number of data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;also helpful in identifying what to ask during interviews&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tips:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;less is more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;be aware of bias&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tie them to inventory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;test them out&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iterate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Questions in survey:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;be clear: code numbers with what they mean (likert)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;be concise: might be a tradeoff with clear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;be specific: avoid double barrel questions, avoid questions that allow internal conflict&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;be expressive: allow users to be expressive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;be unbiased&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;be usable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-data-gathering&#34;&gt;Other Data Gathering&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;logs, already existing reviews etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iterative-needfinding&#34;&gt;Iterative Needfinding&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Needfinding on its own can be a cycle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;revisiting-the-inventory&#34;&gt;Revisiting the inventory&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Revisit these:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who are the users? Age, gender, level of expertise etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where are the users? What is their environment?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the context of the task? What is competing for user attention?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are their goals? What are they trying to accomplish?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do they need? What are the physical objects/information/collaborators they need?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are their tasks? What are they doing physically, cognitively, socially?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are their subtasks? How do they accomplish those subtasks?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;representing-the-need&#34;&gt;Representing the Need&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User needs can be formulated to somthing usable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Task and subtasks, heirarchy, flowchart, diagram of structural relationships amongst the components in the system and how they interact.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;summarize to task analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;defining-the-requirements&#34;&gt;Defining the Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they should be specific and evaluatable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;functionality, usability, learnability, accessibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;compatibility, compliance, cost&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;used to evaluate the interface going forward&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;direct-manipulation&#34;&gt;Direct Manipulation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;direct-manipulation-1&#34;&gt;Direct Manipulation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Direct manipulation in Human-Computer Interaction (HCI) refers to a style of user interface design where the user interacts with graphical objects on the screen directly and immediately, as opposed to indirectly or through a separate command language. The goal of direct manipulation is to make the interface more intuitive and easier to use by allowing users to manipulate objects and see the results of their actions in real-time. Examples of direct manipulation interfaces include desktop environments like Microsoft Windows and Apple&amp;rsquo;s MacOS, as well as mobile operating systems like Apple&amp;rsquo;s iOS and Google&amp;rsquo;s Android.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invisible interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;directly manipulating to perform a task (touch screen allowing for zooming with hand gesture)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Semantic distane: how hard is it to know how to do sth?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Articulary distance: how hard is it to do sth when you know what to do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Direct manipulation is a powerful method for shortening gulfs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VR is also allowing for direct manipulation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;invisibility-by-learning&#34;&gt;Invisibility by learning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cars are an example&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;leveraging prior expectation and providing quick feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tips-for-invisible-interfaces&#34;&gt;Tips for invisible interfaces:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use affordances: places where visual design suggest how its supposed to be used: buttons for pressing etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know your user: invisible means different things to different uses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Differentiate your user: allow multiple ways of accomplishing something&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let your interface teach: teach users more efficient ways of doing something&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk to your user: ask them what the users are thinking (if they are talking about the interface, it is pretty visible)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;human-abilities&#34;&gt;Human abilities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Input, and how humans react&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Average person can sense and perceive (eyes: color and movement)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visual&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Auditory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Haptic Feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use recognition over recall&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Procedural learning: how to do something&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Declarative learning: knowledge about something&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reducing-cognitive-load&#34;&gt;Reducing cognitive load&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use multiple modalities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let the modalities complement each other&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give the user control of the pace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emphasize essential content and avoid the clutter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Offload tasks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;design-alternatives&#34;&gt;Design Alternatives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;after having a good understanding of needs of our user, brainstorm on task we have been investigating&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;but it is hard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;distance yourself from existing solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tunnel vision: focusing on one alternative from the very beginning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design space: the area in which we design our solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;explore possible design space (brainstorm lots of potential spaces)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;generate lots of ideas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;start with individual brainstorming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;groups tend to coalesce around conclusion earlier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tips on individual brainstorming
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write down the core problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Constrain yourself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aim for 20&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take a break&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Divide and conquer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Challenges in Group Brainstorming
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social Loafing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conforormity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Production blocking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performance matching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Power dynamics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rules for Group Brainstorming
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expressiveness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nonevaluation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quantity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stay focused, No explaining ideas, revisit the problem, encourage others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5 Tips for group brainstorming
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go through every individual idea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find the optimal size&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set clear rules for communication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set clear expectations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;End with ideas, not decisions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flesing out ideas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create personas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User profiles (explore the full design space)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Timelines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scenarios and Storyboards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;design-principles-and-heuristics&#34;&gt;Design Principles and Heuristics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discoveribility: visible and users should know or easily figure out what they can do (but walk a line between discoverability and simplicity)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Similicity: understood with little effort and experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Affordances: the design of the things affords or hints at how it is supposed to be used (however we cannot add affordances to design, we can only add signifiers)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mapping: (think about multiple monitors)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perceptibity:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consistency: be consistent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flexibility: (accelerators/hotkeys for expert users, but should cater to wide range of individual preferences)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Equity: design is userful and marketable to people with diverse abilities. Equity is all about making sure users have similar user experience, and flexibility allows for the means to get there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ease and Comfort&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Constraints: limitting the set of possible actions (to make sure users do not use wrong input, and help users with right input)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tolerance: Support undo, redo. The design should be flexible and tolerant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feedback: (worst example: blue screen of death)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation: (avoid this all together, but good to have)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mental-models-and-representations&#34;&gt;Mental Models and Representations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understanding to the world around you, that you hold in your head&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Five Tips:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Predictability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Synthesizability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiarity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generalizability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consistency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analagies might make things better, but they can also hinder progress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are not your own user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>