<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>world bank on Ayush Subedi</title>
    <link>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/categories/world-bank/</link>
    <description>Recent content in world bank on Ayush Subedi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ayushsubedi.github.io/categories/world-bank/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data in News Revisited</title>
      <link>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/data_in_news_revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/data_in_news_revisited/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data in News</title>
      <link>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/data_in_news/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/data_in_news/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-in-news&#34;&gt;Data in News&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://datainnews.ml/&#34;&gt;Link to the website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ayushsubedi.github.io/img/datainnews.png&#34; alt=&#34;feature&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How journalists use data in their reporting or in their writing can be viewed as a reflection of the country’s demand for statistics and data. The report team, in partnership with the Society of Economic Journalists-Nepal (SEJON), organized a roundtable with 38 economic journalists, editors, and bureau chiefs in Nepal to discuss data use in news organizations. The team also administered an online questionnaire to 28 media professionals (see appendix A for the questionnaire and appendix B for the results). To complement these findings, the World Bank team developed an indicator model to assess the use of data by Nepali news portals based on the methodology proposed by Klein, Galdin, and Mohamedou 2016. The results show that very few news articles indicate the source of data or mention development indicators. However, articles that discuss data, reports, research, statistics, and related topics do critically engage with these ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than 4,100 articles were analyzed to assess the use of data in media. The data was collected between 9th December 2019 to 9th February 2020. The data source for the model was Nepali news portals that support RSS feeds and are published in English. The news portals that meet these criteria are the &lt;em&gt;Himalayan Times&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Onlinekhabar&lt;/em&gt;, the &lt;em&gt;Nepali Times,&lt;/em&gt; the &lt;em&gt;Telegraph Nepal,&lt;/em&gt; the &lt;em&gt;Kathmandu Tribune&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Lokaantar&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results of the analysis are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level 1 analysis&lt;/strong&gt;: The team analyzed whether articles indicated the presence of a data source, a statistical/development indicator, or keywords from papers on statistical capacity–building projects. Examples of keywords included &lt;em&gt;household survey, population census, geospatial data, GDP, GNP, pay gap, trade balance,&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;unemployment rate.&lt;/em&gt; The keywords for data sources are comprised of word sequences of length two and scraped from &lt;a href=&#34;https://klein.uk/literacy.html&#34;&gt;https://klein.uk/literacy.html&lt;/a&gt;. The share of news articles that included at least one keyword that indicated “consistent non-critical” &lt;a href=&#34;https://worldbankgroup-my.sharepoint.com/personal/rkumar17_worldbankgroup_org/Documents/PKPS/Open%20Data%204%20Business%20(OD4B)/New%20OD4B/OD4B/DRAFT/Ravi/Feb%2010/EADU%20Feb%2011%202020%20-%20DRAFT.docx#_ftn3&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;use of data averaged 7.6 percent (scores ranged from 2 percent to 12 percent).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level 2 analysis&lt;/strong&gt;: This level of analysis assessed whether an article critically engaged with topics of data or statistics or made arguments by using mathematical concepts. Examples of keywords included &lt;em&gt;ambiguous, error, bias, fake, impartial, precise, scientific,&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;unreliable&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://worldbankgroup-my.sharepoint.com/personal/rkumar17_worldbankgroup_org/Documents/PKPS/Open%20Data%204%20Business%20(OD4B)/New%20OD4B/OD4B/DRAFT/Ravi/Feb%2010/EADU%20Feb%2011%202020%20-%20DRAFT.docx#_ftn4&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Seventeen percent of the more than 4,100 articles studied directly referenced data, records, research, statistics, or studies. Two-thirds of those articles included keywords.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level 3 analysis&lt;/strong&gt;: “Critical mathematical” use of data occurs when an article indicates questioning or interpreting of data and statistics. Examples of keywords included &lt;em&gt;data manipulation, lead question, report bias, sample select,&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;sample size&lt;/em&gt;.  No article met this criterion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/4l8DF1hdD_KNRaL33Ege3cpggTooX_M55IrWVo18k3xAdu7kI58cZsW_yanAkh0fuDr_gqCWXHNKP-Oj11lSB0oei94cHMi0bOeGYQeNH5FC29vzpOK8zncuOKaiLF18pozMmiTj&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nepal Data Literacy Program</title>
      <link>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/nepal_data_literacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/nepal_data_literacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;nepal-data-literacy-program&#34;&gt;Nepal Data Literacy Program&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataliteracy.github.io/images/header3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;header&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nepal Data Literacy Program is designed to catalyze stronger data-driven decision-making by government and non-government actors (mass media, civil society, and academia) through targeted Data Literacy Workshop to help Nepal achieve its development goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The program comprises a 100 hour modular, customizable pedagogy to support both technical skills-building and efforts to enhance a ‘culture of data use’ among Nepalis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the event, my responsibilities were to develop course materials for Python and Machine Learning. Additionally, I was also tasked with reviewing course materials for other modules (Tableau, Statistics, Survey Methodologies etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, I also developed the Nepal Data Literacy website that hosts the entire curriculum, instructor&amp;rsquo;s note, student&amp;rsquo;s workbook, analysis notebooks, datasets, participants projects, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ayushsubedi.github.io/img/dataliteracy.png&#34; alt=&#34;website&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the event, I instructed Python and Machine Learning, including topics of Regression and Classification to industry experts on different fields (Academics, CSO, Media, Entrepreneurs, Managers, NGOs). This was exciting because two of my teachers who taught me in grade 8 were my students in this event. They were proud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-content-created-for-unit-7&#34;&gt;The content created for Unit 7&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/e/2PACX-1vTlceRpdtN_42Fq1d0YxgOIIZJl6HdGP6GwrbZaAS2-Oaf0N1lYjS63u-Dm1XTjgezb7LCTrgPRevE3/embed?start=false&amp;loop=false&amp;delayms=3000&#34;frameborder=&#34;0&#34; width=&#34;720&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; mozallowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; webkitallowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;supplement-materials&#34;&gt;Supplement Materials&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/open?id=1clLQ1O9hqLyWTi5oEnO2kghgDR6MMAB0_IuYUu0vCrY&#34;&gt;Student Workbook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/open?id=1rVQSjYNJ6tdilA4wiLxRVPp21cNpSSEyPcSHneUu6_Q&#34;&gt;Instructor Note&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/open?id=165ALf-XnC9ZHSkuVpSdYhiOdi4NZtG_v_fbbnb8kMfw&#34;&gt;Downloadable Slide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;google-colab-files&#34;&gt;Google Colab Files&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1ywtKMeaXitdIMbBF0n3vz_cvrbMOMwSp&#34;&gt;Python Basics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1X43SiE3bvWErQnrDeC1rUpQ4RDae3Gmc&#34;&gt;Python Basics (Solutions)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1O4bEoAq2xPV5h1s7AG0cM3h8GoM0uxxg&#34;&gt;Probabilities in Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1LygekNV9va00iRF2wMNIVHEQYTMx2YyW&#34;&gt;Probabilities in Python (Solutions)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1LPP7Kvso-zgS2CLYgG70UvEl2A4WSTmk&#34;&gt;Introduction to Seaborn for visualization&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1A2nRZaMkhmhdAAoE3x7Xbr78DEKq4ErF&#34;&gt;Introduction to Pandas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1Mn9DzyXtlkn-PIqgyMdv6IECWdJFDyIB&#34;&gt;Linear Regression&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1LeqK14vDQIpNFVrmk_8x-CY0Rr9atT2w&#34;&gt;Logistic Regression&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spirathon AI Conference 2019</title>
      <link>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/spirathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/spirathon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;journey-to-spam-detection&#34;&gt;Journey to Spam Detection&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spiralogics is hosting a first of it&amp;rsquo;s kind, AI Conference in Nepal this February - a platform for AI veterans and students to come together and network.
This year, Spiralogics is focused on exploring and explaining the ways how AI can create positive impact on different aspects of our life. It is a platform which will act as a driving force in encouraging the implementation of AI (especially in the Nepalese environment). Their purpose is to bring together professionals and students under one roof to rediscover the possibilities that AI can create in our day to day lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ayushsubedi.github.io/img/spirathon.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Spirathon&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-was-i-involved&#34;&gt;How was I involved?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was asked to teach a 5 hour session to introduce the students to a concept of AI. I decided to conduct a workshop based session on Naive Bayes Classifier to detect spam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;topics-covered&#34;&gt;Topics covered&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Probability Primer:&lt;/strong&gt; We look into some few probability problems and Monte Carlo Simulations to get a basic primer on probability and Python.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conditional Probability&lt;/strong&gt;: We look into few examples on conditional probability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bayes Theorem:&lt;/strong&gt; We connect Conditional Probability with Bayes Theorem.  We move from what we know to what we can infer and connect the dots.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sensitivity, Specificity and Confusion matrix:&lt;/strong&gt; We look into concepts of Sensitivity, Specificity, TP, TN, FP and FN. We also look into Type I and Type II errors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accuracy, Precision and Recall:&lt;/strong&gt; We look into different ways to evaluate our models and realize when one is more important than the other. We also study F1 score which combines Precision and Recall.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Naive Bayes:&lt;/strong&gt; We move from Bayes Theorem to Naive Bayes and define what Naive means.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NB Spam detection classifier&lt;/strong&gt;: We build a binary classifier using Scikit learn and publicly available SMS datasets. We also evaluate our model’s performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NB vs Bagging, Random Forest and Adaboost&lt;/strong&gt;: We will not spend much time here. This notebook basically compares Naive bayes with other algorithmns for the same dataset.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ayushsubedi/naivebayes_spirathon2019&#34;&gt;github repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solveathon Nepal 2019</title>
      <link>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/solveathon_nepal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/solveathon_nepal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-solve-a-thon&#34;&gt;What is a Solve-a-thon?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dataliteracy.github.io/images/main_feature.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;solveathon_feature&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A two-day Solveathon, the first of its kind, was organized by the World Bank and The Asia Foundation with support from UKAID at the Kathmandu University School of Management on 14-15 December. The event brought together data scientists, programmers, developers, researchers, and professionals with diverse backgrounds and provided them a platform to work collaboratively on data-driven projects to tackle developmental challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the event, the participating teams worked with mentors and respective domain experts to come up with solutions, refine them and devise various prototypes. The participants worked on nine different projects – three culminated from the 100-hour Nepal Data Literacy Program organized by the World Bank, three proposed by the participants, and three selected by the team based on the pertinent developmental issues and availability of data. The Solveathon will award a total amount of 10,000 USD, divided among two to five projects, to further develop their prototypes. In this phase, the awardees will assess and validate the feasibility of proposed prototype– assumptions in the theory of change, analyze user needs, develop sustainability and action plan–, identify potential partners, and analyze whether similar projects are existent or being planned in the market. Implementation and Review Phase: Under this phase, the awardees will implement their idea or prototype, evaluate its success and demonstrate plans for sustainability of impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was part of the planning and execution committee, and a technical mentor to the participating team. Additionally, once the projects were submitted, I also was part of the team that judged the team based on various criteria such as complexity, sustainability, cost and team members. Three of the projects from the event have started taking good shape at the present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was also responsible for creating the event website which you can find &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataliteracy.github.io/solveathon/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.worldbank.org/content/dam/photos/780x439/2019/dec-2/solvathon.png&#34; alt=&#34;event&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>