<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>android on Ayush Subedi</title>
    <link>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/tags/android/</link>
    <description>Recent content in android on Ayush Subedi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 04:01:02 +0545</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ayushsubedi.github.io/tags/android/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Edquake</title>
      <link>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/edquake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 04:01:02 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/edquake/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-F9T_4XWrLWI/V_Mq01LcubI/AAAAAAAAFWs/R9b8VPWqyYQJF6Zc8VfXMK4XJBj5avpGwCLcB/s1600/app_icon.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The objective of the game was to use texts, audios, videos, badges, quizzes, points, stories and characters to educate users on preparation for earthquake and decision making during and after earthquake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/WqtzEdJfNSNT2C5SwfFDEtKsU5Lrk0xKLHIovgFJkYGAQrTQ1pjxhA7UlnSKJEO0Ul2eyT_n2-DIzKxULxlZhsgbzd2Sb4rPxhnO0Hylj3ABLyZmJZJ9tzfh1uEZCJf6_9FIp2P5&#34; alt=&#34;introvideo.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the game starts, a teaser video is played where an event of earthquake is shown inside a home scenario. The video is shown in order to reflect the importance of earthquake preparedness. The video can be skipped the next time as per the choice of the player.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application Home Screen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application home screen allows users to start a new game, resume from where they left off previously, change game settings such as sound and language settings and submit their score to leaderboards, and quit the application. It also displays current user name and character selection along with all the badges that the user has won.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/oIWHVynC4ePa3xCN8XG2elUGZ2-eq_u-6Qd5ZANZfQo2ap4yVL991phcz0fV59erHbTVwZvIP2Dpq1GMEfO_77NyfpUrCuZso5nqEZUig0sSZyWG2MIVb42yIOQwxj1GxWlS33WP&#34; alt=&#34;home.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Starting a new game&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon starting a new game, a dialog appears where the user enter his/her name and selects a character. The user can choose two characters that of a boy or a girl in order to play the game. These characters will also act as protagonists in animated stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/3I7fr1MuTdBwWjHG61LegJ2uMSqIVQO71Pp-EE84EZGyqU-UasbGVJRlIbYt-iZW6RVRC5TE5iNMZ1DWA_1iwZ2xh6y__63LiPx02w3Ip8ysWyy5XcVqKBILCxmOmu2tW-aDvW8A&#34; alt=&#34;newgame.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Badges&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Badges are provided to users upon completion of a milestone or a level. The badges provides an incentive for the players and makes the game more engaging and interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/FwUlooxiHXdSxTRwmtWRoAxYVFopXNKXysDfClxWAtzNys-RfmSHimhcSr9ydO6uBa582vDP8sxRSXoT52nLzdt7s7Jcatt8IJ3wpGHMdOX93daCwnw57cUbOKy2UfltYMyKONE&#34; alt=&#34;badge.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PSA and Video Activities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engines have been setup to support audio and video activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The radio can be used as an informative element in the game. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A PSA for earthquake preparation informing about vital items one needs in their emergency backpack can be played in the radio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The video platform can support a series of storytelling addressing to different type of circumstances and safety tips regarding the effects of earthquake. Nepali subtitles also appear on the bottom of each videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/CluwZbm53BdQ5boMC6g36wFSWbL8owIk5NFhJLZ0PIwaxypkCHJ3A3wAxegXkAqeLslaGhurVzBn6R3eERk38RvI-xCm5Z5Q9GSlTAhMOzEaEglTc3ufHC7NnGaxqvbxGmEJXojl&#34; alt=&#34;video.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/8Tjm-tIquE2X07NVwO5XEqe3fhNAGyBHZojpL_60QmgmTdU4nyV3fLSKuCzAuLuYMiMAaXBnxDlY66aLckRA2Yp5QHXKBuaA3jYOL3fKNojx3QDBquuD_qHt8mYKUwnec6G6OmM&#34; alt=&#34;psavideo.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drag and Drop Activity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engines have been setup to support drag and drop activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on this drag and drop engine we have developed relevant games. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preparing a GoBag&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the PSA, the users are required to drag and drop items from a set of vital items (such as first aid kid) and useless items (such as toys) to their backpack. Since the backpack can only hold a certain number of items, the users will have to optimize for best preparation. Upon completion, the app lets the users know if their selection is correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/69MzYc05ZZG6yu7HKm9y6tR4MxwHV_aX3OflB803ZHcwp2xah2y6g_ajm4HsVMJkhBEAhxUYS_HATvPaaNOqLu1pK3loLH2zKs1xLnIxNByKnkUJWQHfVb_WbUPQstzYb-Q59hIT&#34; alt=&#34;gobag.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/ai4GfFjSUQAYClVGGIWva3oVp2JqHBU5-xff1G_-QOkhotg9rIszF6FlIB0XsJT-X2mtIVg7FHg1niPHCwdZ6IZjgCXH0vcuTUeZJ31VhDGzm0PLuFdWxArWjd9ADQ3mZ4hd38dy&#34; alt=&#34;resultgobag.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, the app will let the users know if their selection was wise. In case of wrong selection, the app will also let the users know why their selection was incorrect. Unlike other quiz activities, the difference here is that the users will still be allowed to go back to change their answer. The rationale was to follow a formative teaching approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quiz Engines&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engines have been setup to support quiz platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quizzes produces better organization of knowledge by helping the brain organize material in clusters to allow better retrieval. It also identifies gap in knowledge and lets people know what is learned and what is not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quiz engines supports quiz games which can be very informative. The answers chosen can also lead to some consequent information or videos later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are four different types of quiz questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grid Select&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;True and False&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple Choice Questions (3 Options)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple Choice Questions (4 Options)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first two types of questions carry a marking rubric of 200 points. The user receives complete points if he/she answers it correctly in the first go. The point a user can collect from each quiz is reduced depending on the number of mistakes.The third question carry a marking rubric of 300 points and the fourth question carry a marking rubric of 400 points. Similarly, depending on the mistakes, the point is reduced. The result is displayed with additional tip information and graphics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example 1: Grid Quiz Activity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/2ITZwj6fUgwu7Bb_0ec0g7LEhNe5Z6P_Dkt_a-5xvZm7gazrRyh1sQodr_FjWMkF4w2qJJ0XwFDIQonMOeM3QgsuC1XsPnhjvnVyboTmp9IYhQ-tx7z_Fjc8MNcZ2WLvNPq4Sz_N&#34; alt=&#34;gridquestion.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/WztWvUAaXPQwn5Rcqk-d_o4XxU3ork_zpLHbg2oXRMw3ZfOcC7ewHhw1D9sVIOb-Kfc2F6JYTUYl4GSMB02sdYc33mJBgvEmmIecn6TQ3VXKHg29bQF8WfkxmrsdpqXY_tkwc9ad&#34; alt=&#34;gridtip.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example 2: Multiple Choice Quiz Activity (3 options)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/WZVvS4rQXp6qCbO6thPJiltwl_KnZznBWIQEf8iI7Q5uSStg7SuKkPVNCJSP4GKH_ne0b91_wT4Go27TBOf_uSNxooxQz2_nOtJaRKcHvN2kuAHvbefBn-YW7f1PFFxI2I-N84dE&#34; alt=&#34;quiz3.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/wdafblASu42lSEY-50jES3O35KGUhWb8CA0VN4vj8n_QBameDsFpHIM26hY79H01bWdj9KnQKp8BcynerxGfsnBqj3gH__hSLWgbkrBwI_h8N3yb7DgB5LVHo22F1k_eswKxowWd&#34; alt=&#34;tip.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leaderboards and Facebook sharing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application will allow users to submit their points to a global leaderboards system. This will allow users to compete with other players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/UCWt40HM_5shPllWkHS_AZlZo8GSZN7TsxCM-LPO8FWgA675PHU28BN6Rr1e11gPpV4jdqarUZ7lGnUUnuJWmlkeL2X3FaXf7njPOTIHfqoU1nDDxlAwL2N7fdwOlPcSI7icXd1O&#34; alt=&#34;leaderboards.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-uwmYsHlEUBc/V_OBYKgYBEI/AAAAAAAAFXQ/Pf3ySXoIIlw832JDTGFat0HvIyauso3mgCLcB/s640/initiativeshare.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edcrayon</title>
      <link>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/edcrayon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 02:21:02 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/edcrayon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Edcrayon’s &lt;strong&gt;Universal Deployment Model&lt;/strong&gt;, converts tablets or phones to a smart, self-paced, predictive learning environment. It packages the following features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thousands of qualitative educational content that students can browse from and download for offline use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gamified and engaging UI to make sure students love learning from the application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serves as supplement to topics being taught in school or simply for self-study.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Available in different languages to facilitate mother tongue learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning materials is localized and contextualized too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provides practice lessons and quizzes auto-graded by the application so that the students can work their way through the assessments as in self-paced learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Features quiz engines that adapts to students previous knowledge on a particular subject material. If a student struggles with a specific type of problem the application will generate more questions of similar type.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provides performance charts and allows students to track their own performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facilitates discussion forums to allow students from different places to discuss and share ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The performance data will also be sent to regional or central data repository for analysis purposes. The data will help decision makers to facilitate better or different features and contents to ensure more productivity and performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current challenges in education&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delivery of published books to every part of the country has been a significant problem due to the expenses involved in publishing and also due to the lack of road infrastructure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even in cases where books are delivered on a timely basis, it only facilitates traditional teacher-centered teaching pedagogy. Twenty first century education calls for individualized learning which cannot be achieved since published books are not tailored to learners specific needs. Not all students get the optimum learning value from text based materials alone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Several schools have a large teacher to student ratio. Teachers also invest a huge portion of their time on things like keeping comprehensive performance records of every student, preparing and keeping track of lesson plans, and various other administrative tasks. If a system aided the teachers with these mundane tasks, the time saved can instead be utilized for student teaching and classroom engagement. Individualized attention can be provided to the students even in classes where the ratio is high.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decision makers in schools do not have all the performance data of all students and/or teachers at all time. A quantitative analytical report of performance with historical data assists in decision making processes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Schools still follow standardized and summative assessment system. This is partially because the system is inherent in us. However, we believe that the main reason is simply logistical. Large student size, lack of formative assessment tools, lack of engines to create individualized assessment etc. are some contributors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use of technology in education can facilitate myriad of tools that help in solving the challenges. Edcrayon facilitates easy delivery of qualitative media contents, smart algorithms and/or modules that allow for individualized learning via tailored content pushing and group creation, self-paced learning, smart performance charts, and formative and summative assessment models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-eXZ9VM-OWZM/V_MVakbmxDI/AAAAAAAAFUg/EfhsVuZsws0Zw-ftKJA021kg_xIaoGt7wCLcB/s640/Picture1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, private schools have benefitted from Edcrayon’s &lt;strong&gt;Classroom Deployment Model&lt;/strong&gt;. This deployment model converts a traditional classroom environment to technology based, student-centered model. It packages the following features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Constitute all the elements of &lt;strong&gt;Universal Deployment Model&lt;/strong&gt; with an addition to a guided learning and teaching environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replaces the traditional learning and teaching classroom environment to a student centered, formatively assessed, skill based, interactive learning and teaching environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rather than learning at their own pace, which has its own merits, this approach allows students to communicate and learn from teachers and other students in the classroom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facilitates teachers with student performance charts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allows teachers to assign tailored materials for more individualized learning approach.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facilitates formative and Inquiry based assessment through continuous feedbacks from teacher and other students.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performance data of students and teacher are available to decision makers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Government proposed Continuous Assessment System is implemented.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Makes it very easy to perform day to day tasks such as attendance, register keeping, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-qF84ESiz8oE/V_MVyl9kXkI/AAAAAAAAFUk/BuinU2WVf5EvSO0RQvXFSP2HsXh-ObyjQCLcB/s640/Picture1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some Screenshots of Android Application:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-C8883IR1tcQ/V_MWU5VvStI/AAAAAAAAFU0/z6aN0vSudLond9e1Yog23Iq6AU0i5vCzQCLcB/s640/1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-A4xB6ScPSKQ/V_MWVhGVVkI/AAAAAAAAFU4/u2iK9bFJgqc-InOsmsXPb20iPl9U9V4nwCLcB/s400/1a.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-wwFQ5yi-xUM/V_MWVz8Z0mI/AAAAAAAAFU8/45M7I4gL5w4tUmjUPbjk_GbZkECh1mipQCLcB/s400/1b.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-Y4XGMr31mh8/V_MWVxt3WLI/AAAAAAAAFVA/e5ONdON2GNkUvx2xyDUGuvGtbzWdvmSdwCLcB/s400/1c.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-g13-VYs9eFM/V_MWWvSXWmI/AAAAAAAAFVE/KDz9JvW_5qgyGP1y5vzsqcfNkUIHOg2hwCLcB/s400/1d.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-NqRBOXa3HDc/V_MWWnUBQHI/AAAAAAAAFVI/CYo0z_s6IKc4gyhnvWhBlXZHGoxTsOiEgCLcB/s640/2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-AT1VQ1zweWM/V_MWW8KJ25I/AAAAAAAAFVM/JDZ9JV4SWxQ91k90FT4ZksdQ0Jnev-bLQCLcB/s640/3.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Xm78ERg-zsI/V_MWXaKdeyI/AAAAAAAAFVQ/Pxb6-EjEgMAV_uCyDHq8YLqvyVh5mpT7ACLcB/s640/4.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-4ICUopDvz1Y/V_MWXvV1g6I/AAAAAAAAFVU/ueQXICt2acAGA_6f1birVx3WwHeXUQY3ACLcB/s640/5.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some Screenshots of Web Application:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Q2BQPkFvWc8/V_MWZs4_JkI/AAAAAAAAFVs/WO-dChISlU0Zo2EeQufDEmIptZKYckatwCLcB/s400/AdminclassroomManagement.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-QzFNzJgA8Hg/V_MWXzZcb2I/AAAAAAAAFVY/q3TG7rqZ-M8RkMo5Z3QPdyn2kj0LM4CLQCLcB/s400/AdminHealthManagement.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/--9mIhWMeG24/V_MWYT67p-I/AAAAAAAAFVc/fYhJ8xYXxKwKp_IZrRDX-DGq5nSYgcSBQCLcB/s400/AdminUICharts.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-unOE-mQha9o/V_MWY5LWPyI/AAAAAAAAFVk/pBRnQDkyQNoxKyxh4ylgHJByCBey7CbSQCLcB/s400/AdminUIClassroom.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-J219JDo0oqc/V_MWYy6m5fI/AAAAAAAAFVg/2bopGIoeHg8oZPqK1ICViVY1heldu9TFACLcB/s400/AdminUICourse.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-_Lzsf25EnhA/V_MWZDW11YI/AAAAAAAAFVo/UjGDs-3w5ZMe1KGRhxNh2quTDtsdXrkEACLcB/s400/AdminUserManagement.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My role of R&amp;amp;D engineer and Project Lead incorporated architecting overall logic and process flow of Administrative and TeacherUI consisting User, Content, Classroom, Health and Pedagogy Management System. I also designed and co-developed EdCrayon Android application incorporating offline services, interactive charts, formative pedagogy, quiz engines among other features. Additionally, I developed several database administrative tools, wrote several crons and selenium test scripts, and managed multiple school servers. Similarly, I also trained and mentored junior programmers in programming methodologies and best practices. Additionally, I was also involved in training teachers, school-coordinators and school principal to use EdCrayon. Apart from my primary focus on technology, I also served as a core group member in defining and prioritizing technology investments and business objectives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prototype samples:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B-XDuviH5KgwRmh4RExXOXZiUEE&#34;&gt;Sample 1&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B-XDuviH5KgwUkw2U0IwazU5VUE&#34;&gt;Sample 2&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B-XDuviH5Kgwbm9JU1dGZ3NmM28&#34;&gt;Sample 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Etymology and Ngram</title>
      <link>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/etymology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 03:11:02 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/etymology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-27bPJS8zz2U/VoYeWiH1_KI/AAAAAAAADls/jICpVOc5TgI/s640/device-2016-01-01-120842.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-6Xv1iQcDotc/VoYeXNoE2hI/AAAAAAAADl0/G4zmm32fYlA/s640/device-2016-01-01-120905.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-ea19AL8mOfE/VoYeW9Uo0VI/AAAAAAAADlw/6RkqkRfgaJU/s640/device-2016-01-01-120925.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-gs3TAlYHfVg/VoYeXhZA5tI/AAAAAAAADl4/UgtYJvD8vwg/s640/device-2016-01-01-120949.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-GSujGmWfm54/VoYeYlB6lvI/AAAAAAAADmA/Gh_xPB8BBa0/s640/device-2016-01-01-121445.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-VOXTeCw9gdE/VoYeY6DDGYI/AAAAAAAADmE/7ivZxz8Hl0o/s640/device-2016-01-01-121557.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-lPqt7XqUuQ4/VoYeZpvYGzI/AAAAAAAADmI/iFzvhII5v7g/s640/device-2016-01-01-121745.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It uses MPAndroidChart which allows users to scroll within the graphs too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-361ntSWDTWw/VoYeakNusJI/AAAAAAAADmY/6GmWF_C1fRQ/s640/device-2016-01-01-122005.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-_jzCIzggctw/VoYeaYUrOfI/AAAAAAAADmU/XG3vr349b3g/s640/device-2016-01-01-122031.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neo-literacy app concept</title>
      <link>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/neoliteracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 05:14:01 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/neoliteracy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-EBh3SlPn8Aw/V_SzssccFZI/AAAAAAAAFbM/BsJ4tg8gw_8a54Xo2ZIlJ7gNjqoZEoa0QCLcB/s320/a.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improving Literacy has been one of the biggest challenges faced by the developing world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United Nations underscored the importance of combating inequalities in education in its Sustainable Development Goals (Post 2015 Agenda) as the proposed SDG 4 suggests the international community to “Ensure inclusive and equitable quality education and promote lifelong learning opportunities for all by 2030”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Nepal, the literacy rate for the total population is 57.4 % which shows that the inequalities still persist (CIA World Factbook). Significant portion of the population have been deprived of learning opportunities due to various reasons including early marriage, gender inequalities, social and family pressure to engage into economic activities at an early age etc. Research also suggests that in developing countries, there is very low self esteem among people who are illiterates or semi literates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this digital world, they are even at greater disadvantage. Those with the least amount of schooling will find it increasingly more difficult to participate in the evolving knowledge-based societies, deepening the social divide (Reimers, 2000). There needs to be an innovative approach to match both the education and technological gap. Recent development in the mobile technology provides us with great opportunities to fill this gap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mobile devices offer both affordability and storage capacity which makes it possible to equip with different types of educational content. There are over 5 billion mobile subscribers worldwide today –an astounding number considering the world’s current population which is roughly 6.8 billion (ITU, 2010). The rapid proliferation of mobile technologies throughout the world has brought substantial attention to the potential to leverage the power of these new technologies to address decades old problems, including educational inequalities (see Keen and Mackintosh, 2001; Ling, 2004).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Product / Technology Concept&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ICT tool (Android application) for the training will have different components for learning, assessments, data-collection and data-analysis. The idea is to make the application interactive and to reflect a game-environment where users will be motivated by game elements such as unlocking levels (lessons) as they complete certain tasks. The lessons will be based on the UNESCO’s newly-literate book (Mathani) for Awadhi language (Part-2). However, certain levels from Part-1 will also be added as a means to bridge their previous knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the lessons that will be included for the pilot are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Word formation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic math (addition and subtraction)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paragraph reading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paragraph listening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Word math&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time/Calendar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Filling forms, writing letters etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some forms of assessments/practice lessons that will be included in the pilot are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Android drawing canvas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple choice questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;True/False questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Filling in the blanks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing lessons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following user data will be collected within the application with the assumption that every learner will have a personal device to work on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Level progression data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demographic data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Application usage data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performance data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data can be synced in real-time if Internet connectivity is not an issue. However, in places where connectivity can be a problem, or it is expensive, an alternative approach where data is synced periodically can be utilized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-vhqPvZO2fGs/V_OkaQNcRII/AAAAAAAAFXo/SznggCL6His5uv4Zcoh2zfQ3kwobT5AMACLcB/s640/1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-fDdC85MlZ4s/V_OkXWL1grI/AAAAAAAAFXg/2M8WbXF28SU0GGdJlipR5p9i9ryVD_ClQCLcB/s640/2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-SNP0HYWPBFI/V_Okf01WBrI/AAAAAAAAFXs/TGKwPdGDvKYItPDPhXBwKSAv_AcpCBdnACLcB/s640/3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-rYgc7Yh_gGk/V_OkhJOegLI/AAAAAAAAFXw/C4DHM2yzgp0H0ImRla-ITfe29HK4N4OgwCLcB/s640/4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-cUehi7I6bno/V_OkikCsz_I/AAAAAAAAFX0/k4IlhVNPHyIyhTSkrtY8ljepmgRCttasACLcB/s640/5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-WI5BjKk5YhI/V_Okn9WAw1I/AAAAAAAAFX8/ncHqDAACOvokwPmsjflUiY9N1hbsJWChACLcB/s640/6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-e_lvekTTlxM/V_Okmkzr_fI/AAAAAAAAFX4/nYVTNy_km3kYRwux8yyAKywBsKnSnmKzgCLcB/s640/7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-DKyOlnVYIfM/V_OkwwRmY7I/AAAAAAAAFYE/EJn4QKRgEsQrKRn_PTxILfOEWiUgsmeQwCLcB/s640/8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-rA69aY6q-xI/V_OkwhtJylI/AAAAAAAAFYA/LRt-sAWZ9kU0vVqWqR3hHcoz3BZ6HXaQQCLcB/s640/9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-DZZ0fbDiU40/V_OkabJzIEI/AAAAAAAAFXk/OH2aej6XqMIPXO6O4b77Mzwu6-Dr6WeYgCLcB/s640/10.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Net Promoter Scale (NPS)</title>
      <link>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/nps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2015 04:01:02 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/nps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-TYuOQ1UJLzE/V_PgIfgdzfI/AAAAAAAAFaQ/Z-fVeyyIQm4gG386D_AeGtlePk5LsJCBACLcB/s320/nps.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently stumbled upon a customer loyalty measurement scale termed Net Promoter Scale (NPS in short) via a conversation with a businessy friend of mine who was researching on it. I was truly amazed by the simplicity yet brilliance of NPS. Moreover, this is ideal for someone like me who wants to get honest customer feedback without harassing them with poorly designed questionnaires regarding a product.
The pith of NPS lies in the question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“How likely is it that you would recommend our company/product/service to a friend or colleague?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who respond with a score of 9-10 are called Promoters, and are considered likely to show positive behaviors like repeat purchase and positive referrals. Those who respond with a score of 0-6 are labeled Detractors, and they are believed to exhibit the negative behaviors like driving away from the brand, negative referrals. Responses of 7 and 8 are labeled Passives, and their behavior falls in the middle of Promoters and Detractors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The NPS Calculation formula&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Number of Promoters — Number of Detractors) / (Number of Respondents) x 100&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NPS ranges from -100 to 100 (inclusive).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With me doing the charting part and my friend doing the result implication and significance part we developed a simple NPS calculator app that takes total detractors, passives and promotors to output NPS. Refer to the screenshots below to identify what different NPS score signify.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-yR9Uh-3fjtI/V_PdWVu4SsI/AAAAAAAAFZ8/-oIJzJLRZcosIJ0sq5pXI3dQY27A5QXaQCLcB/s640/device-2016-07-28-134536.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-CuzujNNn7h0/V_PdW0rI7iI/AAAAAAAAFaA/_VpTJjIk7bMbOC-OmfvJfJ-0LQQrwFp2QCLcB/s640/device-2016-07-28-134930.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9LbkQR3dmIo/V_PdWO6Ze6I/AAAAAAAAFZ4/EHBiqOCcElkuDcyjjs7yxSXxEGPQ2y47QCLcB/s640/device-2016-07-28-135017.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-iYDH-ZWLyzg/V_PdXWu_eXI/AAAAAAAAFaE/u5T-JsYLZYIqGVolndwWWPW2WbGT4qlqACLcB/s640/device-2016-07-28-135116.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swahili Phonics App with Stanford University</title>
      <link>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/swahili/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 04:04:01 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/swahili/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-y96E-gUxTHg/V_OyFH5pvzI/AAAAAAAAFZQ/sJq-MsOyTbMDMekRrCQdvIo92hp5-zVXACLcB/s320/icon_big_green%2Bcopy.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had contributed as a debugger on Seeds of Empowerment&amp;rsquo;s Swahili Phonics application a while back. This blog post lists various test cases for Swahili Phonics Learning Application for identification of completed requirements and current issues. Thereafter, it also lists the problems that were solved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. User interface and interaction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application has great user interface. Since the majority of targeted users are young children, it is important to make learning fun. This application successfully does that. The only issue with the user interface is that it does not adapt to the full screen width.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expected screen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-8v7fiTclh7k/V_OsRCdboeI/AAAAAAAAFYg/paCxr6YP5h4uCDdQKB-yphAjnPGJTKRQACLcB/s400/Picture1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current screen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;file://localhost/Users/mac/Library/Group%20Containers/UBF8T346G9.Office/msoclip1/01/clip_image004.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-5Tm4YQ-9JPc/V_OtD3a8yGI/AAAAAAAAFYk/2FX6DxQChkwdmO-SkZyxQUJAgs4CFib5QCLcB/s400/Picture2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Data collection&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application collects all sorts of data from the players and stores it locally in the user&amp;rsquo;s device. The players can re-login using their user-name and password and the application allows continuation from where they left before. The application also stores every hits and misses of a user. Although not currently implemented, the data can be used for analysis purposes to identify things like what set of phonetic sound players mostly struggle with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Algorithm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the application provides a great framework for scalability, localization in different languages, and analytics there are few issues that we feel need some attention. We have been able to identify the following problems. We were not really sure if these problems were known since the realization came from analysis of the code rather than from the use of application. Therefore, we decided to list these problems with screen-shots so that it becomes more easier to understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I) random number generation problem&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the current implementation, random numbers help generation of correct and incorrect answer. However, correct answer is always selected from the current level the player is at but incorrect answer set is generated from level 1 through current level. Because of this, although the options will have certain phoneme that are from previous level, they will never be the correct answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a user is at level 2, the correct option will never be from level 1. To generalize, if the user is at level n, the possible set of answers will only be from the phonemes allocated for that particular level n and not from any levels less than n.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-4kZPZ1Oj9FA/V_OtXaQ9McI/AAAAAAAAFYo/U7_EF5zVbDguuw2qmWANgcJpuZtRyr18gCLcB/s400/Picture3.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this case, the answer only be “bo”, “be” or “bi”.
With progression of levels, it becomes more noticeable:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-gQxkkHxsUBs/V_OtuSpMGwI/AAAAAAAAFYw/77qh7ilu6fEv2LYTKy0Zbo7GRN0lW7uqgCLcB/s400/Picture4.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here the possible answer is only one (ie. 4). Also, with the progression of levels, the answers will most likely be the option that the user has not seen before. The game will not chose any phonemes as correct that were part of the option set in previous levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;II) the phonemes are always chosen from a statically defined list&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the game always refers to a single static list of phoneme for selecting correct and incorrect options, it does not adapt to re-test previous misses of a user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/--6Mit95kxAA/V_Ot573LoHI/AAAAAAAAFY4/3brgLpqUxqAXuvQzmRibKeHkR4aoe4bUwCLcB/s400/Picture5.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;III) chances of missing some phonetics because of dynamic array creation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application generates a list during application runtime to check if all phonemes for a particular level have been tested. If a phoneme is tested twice in a level and the player chose the correct answer again, the stars are not increased because the generated list already has the phoneme. It was added to the list when the player answered correctly the first time around. This is a great implementation. However, there is also a small issue with this. Since the list is generated during runtime but the number of stars a player has in a particular level is stored and retrieved when the player re-logins, chances are, some phonemes are never tested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An example,
If Player A starts the game, and in Level 1 he/she successfully recognizes phonemes for {a, e, o, u}, the screen-shot would look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-_67WBXDDGLU/V_OuqlQsQ6I/AAAAAAAAFZA/lM1zxuLjOH8KToIth35dLJXmQZ0XyLtQACLcB/s400/Picture6.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the player is playing the game, the game initializes an array and stores all the successful hits exactly once. The list has “a”, “e”, “o”, and “u” at this point. The player is promoted to another level when he/she has five stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stars are increased if a phoneme can be added to a list (the condition being it does not already exist in the list). In this case, the stars will only be increased if the phonetic for “i” is tested and the player successfully answers that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, if the player decides to leave the game at this point to continue at another time, the array that stored all previous successful hits will be reset. Although he/she will still have 4 stars, now all it takes to move to another level is to identify the first phoneme put by the game. Because of this issue, the might progress to next level without having to identify phoneme for “i”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Adaptability&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This feature is currently missing because it depends on algorithm design. Once the issues are resolved in that part, the next step would be to work on adapting the levels to test users on previously missed phonetics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Report Generation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the application successfully collects useful data, the data is currently not being utilized for analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identified solutions for aforementioned bugs:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solutions have already been implemented in the application. Currently, only algorithm specific problems have been solved. The application still needs additional design and game elements to make it more interactive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-HA7bVCjvbCs/V_O1Tkgyh_I/AAAAAAAAFZg/44LqPGP445EhEaZ29KfxdmTresDLnmWwACLcB/s640/Screen%2BShot%2B2016-10-04%2Bat%2B7.41.39%2BPM.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lost Brothers</title>
      <link>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/thelostbrothers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 12:11:45 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/thelostbrothers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-jB1157xl870/UznA7_yh_qI/AAAAAAAACfc/rioorJr5fhQ/s1600/Bdc6oaRT9.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For quite some time now, my father and my uncle have been debating over the coordinates of their houses with respect to each others. Albeit barely 750 meters from each other, there is not much visible reference points or landmarks to figure it out accurately. The blame is on the molasses thick concrete jungle of Kathmandu valley. (Side-note: Kathmandu will soon be synonymous to the word asphyxiation). Although, I sincerely appreciate their curiosity, I think it is time to end this for once and for all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have used photos of my sister (Ashma) and my cousin (Samip) as labels to the directions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The app implements Canvas to &amp;ldquo;draw&amp;rdquo; the direction. The two GPS coordinates (obtained from Google Earth) were hard-coded into the program and Azimuth from orientation sensor was used to calculate the direction. Basically, it is a compass that points the direction from one house to the other instead of pointing North.
Apart from this rather trivial implementation, the code can be modified to achieve some fun/interesting/useful developments. For instance, the direction of Mecca for Muslim prayers is one that comes to mind. Or, it could be modified into a bearing pointer app by using GPS data and some input EditTexts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Code Snippet&lt;/strong&gt;
onCreate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; protected void onCreate(Bundle savedInstanceState) {
  super.onCreate(savedInstanceState);
  mCustomDrawableView = new CustomDrawableView(this);
  setContentView(mCustomDrawableView); // Register the sensor listeners
  Resources res = getResources();
  samip = BitmapFactory.decodeResource(res, R.drawable.samip);
  ashma = BitmapFactory.decodeResource(res, R.drawable.ashma);
  // Fill in correct latitude and longitude
  currentLoc.setLatitude(0.000000);
  currentLoc.setLongitude(0.00000);
  currentLoc.setAltitude(00);
  destinationLoc.setLatitude(0.00000);
  destinationLoc.setLongitude(0.0000);
  mSensorManager = (SensorManager) getSystemService(SENSOR_SERVICE);
  accelerometer = mSensorManager.getDefaultSensor(Sensor.TYPE_ACCELEROMETER);
  magnetometer = mSensorManager.getDefaultSensor(Sensor.TYPE_MAGNETIC_FIELD);
 }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Canvas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; Float azimuth;
 public Bitmap samip;
 public Bitmap ashma;

 public class CustomDrawableView extends View {
  Paint compassAxis = new Paint();
  Paint compassCircle = new Paint();
  Paint compasAarrow = new Paint();

  public CustomDrawableView(Context context) {
   super(context);
   compassAxis.setColor(0xff00ff00);
   compassAxis.setStyle(Style.STROKE);
   compassAxis.setStrokeWidth(2);
   compassAxis.setAntiAlias(true);
   compassCircle.setColor(0xff000000);
   compassCircle.setStyle(Style.STROKE);
   compassCircle.setStrokeWidth(10);
   compassCircle.setAntiAlias(true);
   compasAarrow.setColor(0xff0000ff);
   compasAarrow.setStyle(Style.STROKE);
   compasAarrow.setStrokeWidth(3);
   compasAarrow.setAntiAlias(true);

  };

  protected void onDraw(Canvas canvas) {
   int width = getWidth(), height = getHeight();
   int centerx = width / 2, centery = height / 2;
   /*
    * Drawing the axis and circle Being symmetrical, these don&#39;t need
    * to be rotated
    */
   // Axis
   canvas.drawLine(centerx, 0, centerx, height, compassAxis);
   canvas.drawLine(0, centery, width, centery, compassAxis);
   // Circle
   canvas.drawCircle(centerx, centery, 200, compassCircle);

   /*
    * since this was a pretty small scope app, magnetic north was not
    * changed to real north. See: &amp;quot;GeomagneticField&amp;quot;
    */
   // Used Float instead of float for this check
   if (azimuth != null) {
    // Converting radians to degrees
    float temp = (float) Math.toDegrees(azimuth);
    float bearing = currentLoc.bearingTo(destinationLoc);
    float direction = temp - bearing;
    canvas.rotate(-direction, centerx, centery);
   }
   canvas.drawLine(centerx, centery - 200, centerx, centery, compasAarrow);
   canvas.drawBitmap(samip, centerx + 5, centery - 200, compassAxis);
   canvas.drawBitmap(ashma, centerx + 5, centery - 15, compassAxis);

  }
 }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Screenshots:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-KH6uVX49fFA/Uzu2oY0VCTI/AAAAAAAACgE/5_rfL55f0J4/s1600/ashmatosamip.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-ybjvNLwJseo/Uzu2o-iKgDI/AAAAAAAACgI/ROqtPEWuXA4/s1600/ashmatosamipmenu.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Ri5qmjH9TWo/Uzu2pi_1kRI/AAAAAAAACgU/USFWoFfQSe4/s1600/samiptoashma.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And after some time wasting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-aRNMlhRQy-o/UzwIWzVYEbI/AAAAAAAACgk/8Wh_SAAL3DA/s1600/device-2014-04-02-183459.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android&#43;Arduino RC Car</title>
      <link>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/rc_car/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 11:03:13 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/rc_car/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;androidarduino-rc-car&#34;&gt;Android+Arduino RC Car&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-_8RnAwamLOM/UuxigwOv4HI/AAAAAAAACW4/mW5MxPQ7HdY/s1600/DSC_0027.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ayushsubedi.com/2013/07/androidrccar.html&#34;&gt;previous attempt&lt;/a&gt; was in shambles due to the lack of proper products. This time, I got myself a Sainsmart L293D motor driver (actually a cloned version of the ever so popular Adafruit L293D driver) and a handy four wheel drive chassis. Hereupon, the only adjustment  required was the use of analog pins as digital pins. This is the consequence of the motor driver using up all the digital pins and leaving no pins for the Bluetooth shield. I also hooked up the Arduino to a USB power bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tools used:
~ Arduino Uno
~ 4WD Chassis
~ SainSmart motor driver (L293D)
~ Sunkee 30ft Bluetooth Module
~ Anker 15000 mAh power bank&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-a_8ouJ9TTOU/UuxyfHkp7DI/AAAAAAAACXI/8h4QGB3fCQo/s1600/Untitled-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arduino&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;//Project: Android RC Car
//Author: Ayush Subedi

#include &amp;lt;AFMotor.h&amp;gt; //import Adafruit Motor library
#include &amp;lt;SoftwareSerial.h&amp;gt;// import the serial library
SoftwareSerial newPorts(15, 17); // RX =15= A1, TX=17=A3  
AF_DCMotor motor1(1, MOTOR12_1KHZ); // create motor #1, 1KHz pwm
AF_DCMotor motor2(2, MOTOR12_1KHZ); // create motor #2, 1KHz pwm
AF_DCMotor motor3(3, MOTOR34_1KHZ); // create motor #3, 1KHz pwm
AF_DCMotor motor4(4, MOTOR34_1KHZ); // create motor #4, 1KHz pwm

void setup() {
  newPorts.begin(9600);           
  motor1.setSpeed(255);     // set the speed to 200/255
  motor2.setSpeed(255);     // set the speed to 200/255
  motor3.setSpeed(255);     // set the speed to 200/255
  motor4.setSpeed(255);     // set the speed to 200/255
}

void loop() {  
    while (newPorts.available() &amp;gt; 0)
  {
    char ch = newPorts.read();
    newPorts.println(newPorts.read());  
    executeReceivedCommand(ch);
  } 
}

void executeReceivedCommand(char command)
{
  switch (command)
  {
    //Forward
  case &#39;0&#39;:
    motor1.run(FORWARD);     
    motor2.run(FORWARD);
    motor3.run(FORWARD);
    motor4.run(FORWARD);  
  break;
    
    //Reverse
  case &#39;1&#39;:
    motor1.run(BACKWARD);     
    motor2.run(BACKWARD);
    motor3.run(BACKWARD);
    motor4.run(BACKWARD);
   
  break;     

    //Left : skid steering
    case &#39;3&#39;:
    motor1.run(FORWARD);
    motor4.run(FORWARD);
    motor2.run(RELEASE);
    motor3.run(RELEASE);
  break;
  
    //Right : skid steering
    case &#39;4&#39;:
    motor2.run(FORWARD);
    motor3.run(FORWARD);
    motor1.run(RELEASE);
    motor4.run(RELEASE);
  break;

     //Stall
  case &#39;2&#39;:
    motor1.run(RELEASE);      
    motor2.run(RELEASE);
    motor3.run(RELEASE);
    motor4.run(RELEASE);    
  break;
  }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-cuy1cpGVbTE/Uux-d0HoVHI/AAAAAAAACXY/RiNMCCUG3Ss/s1600/device-2014-02-01-103955.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-BYq7Y80m_CQ/Uux-fb2qPsI/AAAAAAAACXw/CP5jKd5ZeMM/s1600/device-2014-02-01-104054.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-5GwL64mI0GM/Uux-ey1e-eI/AAAAAAAACXk/FtT7x2U8ozU/s1600/device-2014-02-01-104037.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, the Android device sends &lt;em&gt;Char&lt;/em&gt; type to Arduino which is used to rotate the motors to maneuver towards a desired direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forward: 0
Reverse: 1
Stop: 2
Left: 3
Right: 4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The car turns left and right by implementing &lt;em&gt;skid steering&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pictures and Video:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-s2w3-5LZqMo/Uuyr1gptrFI/AAAAAAAACYI/HpUrDAo6bro/s1600/DSC_0033.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-v1Yr71b9nEg/Uuyr5-n2T3I/AAAAAAAACYQ/uPvTKj_qzow/s1600/DSC_0035.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-SbQNev4Xlac/UuytAzkVbWI/AAAAAAAACYc/nDIj4OcxYCc/s1600/DSC_0036.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KiaEGsHsIco&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>