<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>analysis on Ayush Subedi</title>
    <link>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/tags/analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in analysis on Ayush Subedi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 04:09:44 +0545</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ayushsubedi.github.io/tags/analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheers Hospital Analysis</title>
      <link>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/cheers_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 04:09:44 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/cheers_analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;data-analysis-of-cheers-hospital&#34;&gt;Data analysis of Cheers hospital&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it’s inception, Hospital for Children Eye ENT and Rehabilitation Service (CHEERS) has amassed data from various sources such as all the software used in daily operations, research department and the finance department. With priority in budgeting which is always a significant factor, CHEERS wanted Moonlit Solutions to analyze the data from different sectors within the hospital and create forecasting models to help with their operational efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ayushsubedi.github.io/img/cheers.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cheers&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;scope-of-work&#34;&gt;Scope of work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data curation from different sectors of the hospital (but only limited to their Hospital Management Information System)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data wrangling and principal component analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exploratory data analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creation and validation of different forecasting models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assist in the creation of the forecasting section in the hospital master plan that is currently being developed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/13403428/38305927-fc5e91f6-380e-11e8-9e20-7bd866a034a5.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;methodology&#34;&gt;Methodology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the acquisition stage, all analysis presented in notebooks followed the following methodology:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gaining domain expertise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data wrangling and cleaning (a lot of imputing using the domain knowledge and meeting stakeholders)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exploratory Data Analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forecasting with multiple models (AR, MA, ARIMA, SARIMA, Bayesian, Deep Learning)and different KPIs (Daily sales, Daily patient visits)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimization (Parameter tuning)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;outputs&#34;&gt;Outputs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robust forecasting models predicting future sales&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A report document&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dashboard showcasing interactive charts and tables (and all analysis notebooks for research reproducibility)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://miro.medium.com/max/754/1*io2zk4HVTX8764K_fJAerw.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exploratory data analysis and forecasts generated went through various levels of quality assurance to validate the correctness. Unfortunately, the COVID-19 epidemic and subsequent lockdowns was going to affect the business. The model created wasBAU (Business As Usual). It did not forecast out of the world scenarios like COVID-19 (a Black Swan event). However, it will create a benchmark for measuring the effects of COVID-19 in the future. The forecasting can still be used to understand the impact of COVID-19 on the business. The exploratory data on the other hand, provides significant insights for the hospital&amp;rsquo;s strategy development.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data in News</title>
      <link>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/data_in_news/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 09:45:16 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ayushsubedi.github.io/posts/data_in_news/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-in-news&#34;&gt;Data in News&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://datainnews.ml/&#34;&gt;Link to the website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ayushsubedi.github.io/img/datainnews.png&#34; alt=&#34;feature&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How journalists use data in their reporting or in their writing can be viewed as a reflection of the country’s demand for statistics and data. The report team, in partnership with the Society of Economic Journalists-Nepal (SEJON), organized a roundtable with 38 economic journalists, editors, and bureau chiefs in Nepal to discuss data use in news organizations. The team also administered an online questionnaire to 28 media professionals (see appendix A for the questionnaire and appendix B for the results). To complement these findings, the World Bank team developed an indicator model to assess the use of data by Nepali news portals based on the methodology proposed by Klein, Galdin, and Mohamedou 2016. The results show that very few news articles indicate the source of data or mention development indicators. However, articles that discuss data, reports, research, statistics, and related topics do critically engage with these ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than 4,100 articles were analyzed to assess the use of data in media. The data was collected between 9th December 2019 to 9th February 2020. The data source for the model was Nepali news portals that support RSS feeds and are published in English. The news portals that meet these criteria are the &lt;em&gt;Himalayan Times&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Onlinekhabar&lt;/em&gt;, the &lt;em&gt;Nepali Times,&lt;/em&gt; the &lt;em&gt;Telegraph Nepal,&lt;/em&gt; the &lt;em&gt;Kathmandu Tribune&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Lokaantar&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results of the analysis are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level 1 analysis&lt;/strong&gt;: The team analyzed whether articles indicated the presence of a data source, a statistical/development indicator, or keywords from papers on statistical capacity–building projects. Examples of keywords included &lt;em&gt;household survey, population census, geospatial data, GDP, GNP, pay gap, trade balance,&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;unemployment rate.&lt;/em&gt; The keywords for data sources are comprised of word sequences of length two and scraped from &lt;a href=&#34;https://klein.uk/literacy.html&#34;&gt;https://klein.uk/literacy.html&lt;/a&gt;. The share of news articles that included at least one keyword that indicated “consistent non-critical” &lt;a href=&#34;https://worldbankgroup-my.sharepoint.com/personal/rkumar17_worldbankgroup_org/Documents/PKPS/Open%20Data%204%20Business%20(OD4B)/New%20OD4B/OD4B/DRAFT/Ravi/Feb%2010/EADU%20Feb%2011%202020%20-%20DRAFT.docx#_ftn3&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;use of data averaged 7.6 percent (scores ranged from 2 percent to 12 percent).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level 2 analysis&lt;/strong&gt;: This level of analysis assessed whether an article critically engaged with topics of data or statistics or made arguments by using mathematical concepts. Examples of keywords included &lt;em&gt;ambiguous, error, bias, fake, impartial, precise, scientific,&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;unreliable&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://worldbankgroup-my.sharepoint.com/personal/rkumar17_worldbankgroup_org/Documents/PKPS/Open%20Data%204%20Business%20(OD4B)/New%20OD4B/OD4B/DRAFT/Ravi/Feb%2010/EADU%20Feb%2011%202020%20-%20DRAFT.docx#_ftn4&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Seventeen percent of the more than 4,100 articles studied directly referenced data, records, research, statistics, or studies. Two-thirds of those articles included keywords.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level 3 analysis&lt;/strong&gt;: “Critical mathematical” use of data occurs when an article indicates questioning or interpreting of data and statistics. Examples of keywords included &lt;em&gt;data manipulation, lead question, report bias, sample select,&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;sample size&lt;/em&gt;.  No article met this criterion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/4l8DF1hdD_KNRaL33Ege3cpggTooX_M55IrWVo18k3xAdu7kI58cZsW_yanAkh0fuDr_gqCWXHNKP-Oj11lSB0oei94cHMi0bOeGYQeNH5FC29vzpOK8zncuOKaiLF18pozMmiTj&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>